

### PROFILE

I am a human, husband and father, who creates, designs, teaches and occasionally writes. I was born in the suburbs of Chicago, Illinois, but have been living in the southcentral part of Chile for close to a decade.

I am looking for a dynamic and challenging remote employment opportunity where I can use my abilities and talents to grow as a person while increasing the value and identity of the company.

#### **EDUCATION**

2007-2008

**TEACHER CERT. K-12, SPANISH** Eastern Illinois University, USA

1995-2003

**B.A. FOREIGN LANGUAGES (SPANISH)**Eastern Illinois University, USA

1995-2003

B.A. HISTORY, MINOR IN LATIN AMERICAN STUDIES Eastern Illinois University, USA

#### SKILLS

- ✓ Bilingual (English / Spanish)
- ✓ HTML / CSS / JS / JQuery
- ✓ Progressive Web App
- ✓ PHP
- ✓ WordPress / CMS
- **✓** Translation
- ✓ Copy Editing
- ✓ Photography

# **MIKE WALSH**

### DESIGNER / PROFESSOR / TRANSLATOR / WRITER

Address: Casilla 134 / Villarrica / CHILE

Phone: +56 9 99373763

Email: elmikewalsh@gmail.com

Websites: www.elmikewalsh.com // www.imaginalgo.com

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## FREELANCE WEB DESIGNER / DEVELOPER, PROJECT MANAGER OPTUNO | MARCH, 2017 - PRESENT

I help Optuno create websites from start, customize existing themes and manage project content and client requests alongside a wonderful, world-wide remote team.

### ENGLISH PROFESSOR ECLASS | MARCH, 2015 - PRESENT

I was contacted by eClass to be one of their first remote-working Live Class professors. I have provided over 2 years of hard work, dedication and impeccable reputation, which has created a confidence and stability for the remote Live Class product.

# PROGRAM COORDINATOR <u>TEACHINGCHILE</u> | MARCH, 2012 - PRESENT

I have worked in this 100% remote role for over 5 years. In this position, it has been essential to manage and organize multiple projects and needs simultaneously, such as: attention to incoming participant's needs and questions, creation and implementation of a digital strategy, and communication with past and present participants with monthly newsletter.

# DIGITAL PRODUCT & EXPERIENCE DESIGNER IMAGINALGO, LLC | JANUARY, 2007 - PRESENT

I have created and maintained a number of websites for individuals and small to mid-sized companies. I enjoy a special emphasis on clean minimalist sites that load quickly and have a fresh, modern feel. I have created some WordPress themes as well. I have also produced multiple print designs, including: books/e-books, business cards, product labeling, wedding invitations and fliers/posters. I love what I do and take each product mission as if it were my personal "love project".

### **HOBBIES & INTERESTS**

Design / Writing / Photography / Sports